<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Peter Roehlen</title>
    <link>https://peter.roehlen.net/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Peter Roehlen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 11:55:04 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peter.roehlen.net/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m Sticking With UBlue</title>
      <link>https://peter.roehlen.net/posts/sticking-with-ublue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 11:55:04 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://peter.roehlen.net/posts/sticking-with-ublue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using &lt;a href=&#34;https://universal-blue.org/&#34;&gt;Universal Blue&lt;/a&gt; heavily for a week now and it’s a keeper. UBlue is an immutable operating system based on Fedora where you install nearly all of your software as either flatpaks or as packages running in containers. Those containers can be based on any of a dozen different distributions. You &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; install Fedora packages to your base OS similar to a traditional distrubution but the philosopy behind UBlue encourages keeping your base install light and clean. Amongst other things, having a small, light and immutable base system greatly reduces your vector for malware.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Customization Is Like Crack</title>
      <link>https://peter.roehlen.net/posts/linux-customization-like-crack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 22:15:09 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://peter.roehlen.net/posts/linux-customization-like-crack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The ability to customize everything in Linux is like crack after coming from a year of exclusively using Windows. In Windows, a mountain of small daily irritants, that I didn’t have the power to do anything about, all added up to a persistent dull ache in the balls.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Returning to Linux</title>
      <link>https://peter.roehlen.net/posts/returning-to-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 23:18:19 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://peter.roehlen.net/posts/returning-to-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well after a year or something of exclusively using Windows 10/11 and not having Linux, I’m back baby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I installed KDE Plasma so I could configure the taskbar to look/work like Windows 11, installed Microsoft VS Code, Microsoft Teams, Microsoft Edge, Microsoft Powershell and I’m ready to rock and roll.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
